Here's the uniform you ordered.
（さつき）はい！ 注文したユニ
届いたから持ってきたよ！
（黒子(くろこ)）
あ… ありがとうございます
Thank you.
（さつき）ああ…
あと１つ連絡事項
I have a message for you, too.
Starting tomorrow, someone's
joining the first string.
明日から１人 １軍に
上がってくる子がいるんだけど…
I heard about that this afternoon.
（黒子）その話 昼に聞きました
That'll make this quick, then.
（さつき）なら 話早いね！
その彼 バスケ部に入って
まだ２週間らしいの
Apparently it's been only two
weeks since he joined the team.
（黄瀬(きせ)）っしゃあ！
Yeah!
（さつき）だから教育係に
ついてほしいんだって
They want you to mentor him.
名前は 黄瀬涼太(りょうた)
His name is Kise Ryota.
（虹村(にじむら)）虹村です
It's Nijimura.
I've given it a lot of thought,
and I think it's for the best.
よく考えたんですが…—
やはりこうしたほうが
いいと思いました
部にとっても オレにとっても
For the team and for me.
Please make Akashi Seijuro
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)を…
キャプテンにしてください
the captain.
...Sorry
（真田(さなだ)）分からんな
思えば去年 まだ１年の赤司に—
I don't get it.
Last year you asked me to make
first-year Akashi the vice captain.
副キャプテンをすすめたのも
オマエだった
The coach and I both
赤司の資質については
監督も私も感じていたし—
sensed Akashi's potential and
made an exception for him.
例外的にそれを認めたが…—
But why are you in such a
hurry to have him take over?
なぜそこまで急いで
赤司に譲ろうとする？
父が… 去年の春から
入院しています
My father's been in the
hospital since last spring.
今はまだ落ち着いていますが—
He's stable now, but they're not
sure how he'll be by nationals.
全中のころには どうなっているか
分からないそうです
けど もし何かあったら…—
If something happened to him,
試合中ならば それを放り出して
病院に向かいます
I'd abandon the game to go see him.
If I heard his condition worsened,
I wouldn't be able to play.
そうでなくても
悪化の知らせを受ければ—
平静にバスケットなど
できないでしょう
I love basketball, and I was afraid
to accept my father's condition.
バスケは好きだし
父のことを認めるのも怖かった…
That's why I haven't said anything until now.
だから今まで言いそびれてきました
I'm sorry.
本当にすみません
（真田）ハア… 分かった
監督にも伝えておこう
Fine.
I'll tell the coach.
おう 赤司か
Hey, Akashi.
Hello.
（赤司）どうも
ふう… てかオメー…
聞いてやがったな？
You were listening, weren't you?
Just the last part.
最後のほうだけです
一番聞かれたくない
とこじゃねーか…
That's the worst part.
Anyway...
というわけで… 少し早いが
これからオメーがキャプテンだ
It's a little early, but you're
the captain now, Akashi.
赤司
It hasn't been decided yet.
（赤司）まだ 決まってませんよ
It's as good as decided.
決まってるだろ！
あの話聞いて まだキャプテン
やらせる気か？ オメーは
After hearing what I said,
you still want me to be the captain?
Are you uncertain?
不安か？
No. I'm just worried about you.
（赤司）いえ…
虹村さんの
心配をしているだけです
フッ… だろーな
I'm sure you are.
But I'm not worried.
だから オレは
心配してねーわ
よろしく頼むぜ…
赤司キャプテン
I'm counting on you, Captain Akashi.
Yes, sir.
（赤司）はい
（黄瀬）でっ！ ぐうっ！
Kuroko and Kise accompanying
the second string
（緑間(みどりま)）黒子と黄瀬の
２軍同伴の結果は—
turned out exactly as we expected.
思ったとおりだったようだな
Yes.
（緑間）黄瀬も あそこまで
あっさり認めるとは…
I'm surprised you accepted Kise so quickly.
What?
なんだ 緑間はまだ
黒子のことを認めていないのか？
Midorima, you still don't
recognize Kuroko's talent?
No, we do.
とっくに認めているのだよ
オレも 紫原(むらさきばら)も 先輩たちも
Both Murasakibara and I.
And the upperclassmen.
（赤司）ならいいじゃないか
Then there's no problem.
黄瀬はそれが少し早かっただけだ
Kise just got there quicker than usual.
黄瀬のポジションは
あいつとかぶっている
He and Kise fill the same position.
You mean Haizaki?
灰崎(はいざき)か そういえば今日も…
Come to think of it, he...
Yes. The idiot skipped again.
（緑間）ああ サボリなのだよ
あのバカは
だが 残念ながら実力はある
But unfortunately, he's good.
He'll be our starter,
and Kise will be his sub.
ヤツがスタメンで—
（緑間）黄瀬が控えのほうが…
（赤司）いや それは違うな
No, I don't think so.
Haizaki is no match for Kise's
potential and rate of growth.
黄瀬のポテンシャルと成長速度は
灰崎の比ではない
さらに控えは
虹村さんがコンバートされる
Additionally, Nijimura-san
will become the sub.
Haizaki's terrible behavior is intolerable.
（赤司）
灰崎の素行の悪さは目に余る
Keeping him would only hurt the team.
これ以上はデメリットしかない
We no longer need him.
もう用済みだ 退部をすすめよう
I'll ask him to quit the team.
Normally Akashi is calm and mild-mannered.
（緑間）
赤司はふだん 冷静かつ温厚…
実力もあり人望も厚い
He's talented and popular.
But sometimes he becomes
a different, cold person.
だが時々 別人のように
冷たい目になるときがある
いや… 少なくともオレには
別人にしか思えない
At the very least, he seems
like a different person to me.
But if that's the case, which
one is the true Akashi?
だとしたら… 一体どちらが
本当の赤司なのだ？
I see.
（青峰(あおみね)）そっか…
やっぱ灰崎はやめちまったか…
Haizaki quit the team, huh?
Can't be helped, I guess.
（青峰）じゃあ しょうがねえな
（黒子）え…
少し冷たくないですか？
Aren't you being a little cold?
You tried and failed to stop him, right?
（青峰）
オマエが行ってダメだったんだろ？
There's nothing we can do now.
なら しょうがねえとしか
言えねーよ
Haizaki is a proud man.
（緑間）
灰崎はプライドが高いヤツだ
If one of us or the upperclassmen had gone,
オレたちや先輩たちが
行ったところで—
it would've been counterproductive.
逆効果にしかならなかった
はずなのだよ
（黒子）ですが…
（虹村）ったく…
But...
Quit being so soft.
いつまでも甘いこと言ってんな
お互いチームメイトであると同時に
競争相手だ
You're teammates and rivals.
Since when have you become strong
enough to worry about others?
いつから人の心配できるほど
偉くなったんだ
If you've got time for that, run!
ふり返ってるヒマがあんなら走れ！
Gather 'round!
（真田）集合！
（黒子）あ…
We have less than two months
until national qualifiers.
（真田）
全中の予選まで２か月を切った
The coach is taking over command now.
よってここからの指揮は監督が執る
What?
（紫原）えー…
（青峰）マジかよ…
Seriously?
あの… どんな方なんですか？
What's he like?
Oh, right. It's your first time.
あっ そーか テツは初めてか
That's right.
（白金(しろがね)）そうだな…
（青峰）いっ！
（白金）
じゃあ あいさつしておかねばな
I'd better introduce myself, then.
I'm Shirogane Kozo, the coach.
監督の白金耕造(こうぞう)だ
よろしくな 黒子君
Nice to meet you, Kuroko-kun.
（黒子）え？ なぜボクの名前を…
How do you know my name?
Why shouldn't I?
当然だ 選手の名前は
すべて覚えている
I know all my players' names.
（部員たち）チワス！
（白金）ああ 硬くならんでいい
Yes, sir!
You don't need to be so stiff.
He came to practice all the time.
（赤司）練習には よく来ていたよ
（黒子）そうなんですか
Really?
できるだけ選手の素の部分を
見たいそうで—
He likes to see his players
in their natural state,
so he often watches from the second
floor without saying anything.
２階などから 何も言わずに
見ていることが多い
He seems nicer than I expected.
思ったより優しそうな方ですね
You're wrong.
（青峰）それはない
（黒子）あれ？
Huh?
（白金）今までずいぶん
のどかだったからな
Practice has been fairly easy until now.
ここからが本当の練習だ
はるかにハードになるが心配するな
Your real practice starts now.
It will be much harder, but don't worry.
You're young enough that it won't kill you.
若いうちは何をやっても死なん
He's just a total hard-ass.
ただただ 鬼のように厳しいだけだ
（白金）
１つ連絡事項がある 赤司
I have an announcement to make.
Akashi...
はい
Yes, sir.
（白金）今日付けで虹村に変わって
赤司征十郎をキャプテンとする
Starting today, Akashi Seijuro will
replace Nijimura as the captain.
（部員たち）え…
（紫原）マジで？
Seriously?
The third-years may not like it,
（白金）３年生も思うところは
あるだろうが—
but it's so the team can win.
勝つための決定だ 認めろ
You must accept it.
Nijimura, you've done a great job until now.
虹村は今までよくやってくれた
Thank you.
（虹村）ありがとうございます
（紫原）いや〜 ビックリしたね〜
That was a surprise.
I knew he was amazing, but I can't
believe he's the captain already.
すげーのは知ってたけど
まさかもうキャプテンとはなー
But he's still only a second-year...
けど まだ２年生なのに…
大丈夫なんでしょうか？
Can he handle it?
There's nothing to worry about.
（緑間）おそらく心配ないのだよ
（黄瀬）ん？
Akashi comes from a prominent family.
（緑間）赤司は日本有数の
名家の子だ
Seriously?
（黄瀬）まじっスか!?
（緑間）その跡を継ぐため
家は厳しく—
His family has him take
advanced education courses
あらゆる英才教育を
ほどこされている
so he can succeed them one day.
He will pull the team together
だから などと
言うつもりはないが—
even better than Captain Nijimura did.
虹村キャプテンかそれ以上に
チームをまとめる力はあるのだよ
Really?
Midorimacchi, you seem
pretty well-bred yourself.
ってか 緑間っちも結構
育ちよさそうっスよね 実は
Not like Akashi.
赤司ほどではないのだよ
それより紫原
歩きながら食べるのはやめろ
Anyway, Murasakibara,
stop eating while you walk.
（紫原）えー やだー
（緑間）うっ… おい！
No way.
Hey!
（黄瀬）ちょーっと！
（青峰）ん？
Hey...
Do they not get along?
あの２人って仲悪かったんスか？
あー
悪いってほどじゃねーけど—
It's not that bad.
Midorima is pretty uptight,
and Murasakibara's relaxed.
緑間は何事もキッチリしねーと
気がすまねータイプだし—
They've never really liked each other,
紫原は
いろいろルーズなヤツだから—
but it's been especially bad lately.
元からあんま
気は合ってなかったんだけど—
最近 特にな
（黄瀬）
あー じゃ原因はあれっスかね
Is that why, then?
They've been playing really well lately.
最近あの２人 バスケの調子が
すげーいいからっスか？
Why are you standing there?
なぜそんなところに
突っ立っているのだよ！
If you had screened him,
I would've been wide open!
今のはオマエが
スクリーンをかければ—
オレが完全にフリーだっただろう！
What?
はあ〜？ んなメンドクサイこと
やんなくても—
I wouldn't need to do that if
you'd just pass me the ball!
ミドチンがこっちに
パスくれりゃいいじゃん！
（紫原・緑間）ぐうぅ…
（２人）オレが決めたほうがいい
（緑間）のだよ！
I should decide!
（部員）
うわっ ケンカやめろ おい！
Stop fighting!
何をやっとるんだ まったく
What are they doing?
（紫原）だ〜か〜ら〜
I told you...
（緑間）
ダラダラしゃべるな！
Don't slur your words!
What are you going to do, Captain Akashi?
（虹村）おい どうすんだ？
赤司キャプテン
Let's observe a little longer.
（赤司）少し様子を見ましょう
I've had enough.
（紫原）もう やだ〜
（緑間）オレだって嫌なのだよ！
I don't like this, either!
（黒子）ケンカはやめてください
Stop fighting!
Even I could beat you right now.
今の２人なら
ボクでも勝てますよ
（紫原・緑間）ぬう…
Play me after practice,
and I'll prove it to you.
練習の終わった後で
勝負してくれれば証明してみせます
The team that scores ten points first, wins.
（黒子）このチームで
先に10点取ったほうが勝ちです
Akashi
Murasakibara
Midorima
（黄瀬）なるほど…
I see...
We just have to beat them
with our teamwork, right?
（青峰）これでオレらが
チームワークを見せつけて—
（青峰）勝ちゃいいんだろ？
（黒子）はい
Kuroko
Aomine
Yes.
ちょっと赤ちーん
手ぇ抜いてない？
Akachin, are you holding back?
（赤司）まさか
オレはいつもどおりやってるよ
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm playing how I always do.
Sheesh...
（緑間）フン…
What?
（青峰）いっ… ててぇ…
Ow...
What are you doing, Kise?
おい 何やってんだよ 黄瀬ぇ！
Tetsu was passing to me!
今のはテツからオレの
リターンだろ!?
What? That was obviously a pass to me!
なんでっスか！ どー考えても
オレへのパスだったじゃないスか！
What? That was mine!
（青峰）はあ!? オレだろ！
（黄瀬）オレっス！
No, mine!
（２人）
ぐぬぬぬ… くう… うぬぬ…
What?
Why are you fighting now?
（緑間）なぜオマエらも
ケンカを始めるのだよ!?
（紫原）はあ〜… なんかもー
アホらしくなってきちゃったー
This is stupid.
I see how unbecoming it is now, Kuroko.
とりあえず—
みっともないことなのは
分かったのだよ 黒子
（黒子）オ… オエ…
（緑間）吐いてるのだよ！
You're puking?!
Problem solved.
（赤司）どうやら解決したようです
（虹村）ん？ ああ…
Huh?
Oh, good...
（選手１）青峰 50点目！
That's Aomine's 50th point!
（選手２）
なんてヤツだ！ 止まんねえ！
He's unstoppable!
（黒子）失礼します！
Excuse me.
やあ 昨日はご苦労だったね
Good work yesterday.
Huh?
（黒子）
あれ… 青峰君と黄瀬君は？
Where are Aomine-kun and Kise-kun?
（青峰）でいっ！
（黒子）それに 緑間君も…
And Midorima-kun...
You were puking a lot. Are you okay?
ちょー吐いてたけど大丈夫ー？
They're accompanying the
second string to their game.
（黒子）やめてください…
（赤司）彼らは２軍の試合に
同伴している
Don't do that.
They should be playing right now.
今ちょうど やっている頃だろう
Teiko
Harada
（さつき）青峰君…
Aomine-kun?
えいっ！
ハア… ハア… あっ…
（原田選手たち）
ハア… ハア… ハア…
（黒子）青峰君
Aomine-kun...
青峰君！
Aomine-kun!
Why do you look so out of it?
どうしたんですか ぼーっとして
（青峰）いや… なんでもねえよ
It's nothing.
You've been on a roll lately.
最近 調子がいいみたいですね
ああ… まあな
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, listen...
なあ… あ いや なんでもねえよ
Never mind.
You sure?
（黒子）そうですか
Since you adopted your new style,
you've been staring at people a lot.
あ そういや
今のスタイルになってから—
よく周りのヤツ
じーっと見てたりするな
Yes. I'm observing them.
（黒子）はい 人間観察です
（青峰）あ？
Tetsu-kun!
（さつき）
テ〜ツ〜く〜ん！
What?
It's for my Misdirection—
ミスディレクションに
応用する…
（さつき）
テ〜ツ〜く〜ん！
（青峰）
最近テツにグイグイ来るよな
You've been all over Tetsu lately.
I can't help it.
だってー ガマンできないんだもん
（黒子）すみません
早くどいてもらえますか
Let me go, please.
（青峰）
つか 話の腰折ってんじゃねーよ
You interrupted our conversation.
（さつき）えー なになに？
（黒子）ああ そうでしたね
Huh? What?
Oh, right.
（さつき）なんの話？
（黒子）じゃあ桃井(ももい)さん
What were you talking about?
Hey, Momoi-san...
When people look at you,
you tend to look back.
（黒子）桃井さんは見つめられたら
見つめ返すタイプですね
What?
（さつき）え!?
（青峰）なんだよ そりゃ
Say what?
人には さまざまなクセがあり
異なるリアクションがあります
Everyone has their own habits and reactions.
それを観察して分類するんです
I observe and analyze them.
視線の誘導には
そういうことも必要になります
It's a necessary part of
directing someone's attention.
そんじゃあ オレのクセとかも
分かってんのかよ
Do you know what my habits are, too?
You always avert your eyes when you lie.
（黒子）ウソつくときは
必ず目をそらしますね
あー… まいったな…
You got me.
But I won't make you tell me.
（黒子）別に だから話せとは
言いませんよ
Tell me when you feel like it.
そのうち話したくなったら
話してください
（青峰）ああ 分かった
Got it.
（黄瀬）あ いた！
（さつき）あ…
There you are!
You guys want to get ice
cream on the way home?
帰りみんなで
アイス食ってかねーっスか？
Yeah, good idea.
おー そうだな
What about you, Momocchi?
（黄瀬）桃っちは？
（さつき）あ…
I need to take this game data to Akashi-kun.
私 ちょっと
この試合データとか—
赤司君に持ってかないと
いけないから…
（紫原）最近 さっちん
情報収集とかそういうの—
Akachin's been asking you to
collect a lot of data lately.
よく赤ちんに任されてるよねー
（緑間）ご苦労なことなのだよ
Good work.
（さつき）あはは 意外に私
こういうの向いてたみたいで…
Apparently I'm pretty good at it.
Another time, then.
（青峰）じゃ また今度な
（さつき）うん じゃーねー
Yeah. Later, guys.
（黄瀬）いてっ！
Ow!
The third- and second-years have
reached a level of potential
（真田）
虹村たち３年はもちろん—
赤司たち２年生の完成度は
もはや中学生を超えている
far beyond typical middle school students.
過去最強であることは
間違いないでしょう
They're almost certainly
the strongest players ever.
（白金）完成度か
Reached their potential, huh?
Actually, I'd say the opposite about them.
その言い方ならば
むしろ逆だと思うがね
National Middle School Basketball Tournament
Regional Qualifiers
They're still developing.
（白金）まだ発展途上だ
彼らの才能は こんなものではない
They haven't reached their maximum potential.
末恐ろしい子たちだよ
They're terrifying children.
誰が言ったか知らんが—
Someone called them the "Generation
of Miracles." I couldn't agree more.
“キセキの世代”とは
よく言ったものだ
優勝以外ありえん
これは決意ではなく—
There's no way they won't win.
That's not resolve talking.
It's certainty.
確信だ
Congratulations on making
it through the first round!
予選 初戦突破おめでとう！
Uh huh.
（青峰）ん…
（緑間）そうだな
Yes.
Yeah.
（さつき）
あれ!? テンション低い!?
You don't seem very excited!
Actually, why are you so excited?
むしろ なんでそんな
オマエがたけーのか聞きてーよ
We always win.
いつものことじゃん
Kurokocchi's been really
happy since yesterday.
（黄瀬）黒子っちは 昨日から
ずっと幸せそうっスけど
（青峰）テツは公式戦では
初めてだったからな…
It was Tetsu's first time
in an official game.
Winning is good.
まあ 勝ったのは喜ばしいことだ
We'll keep doing what we're doing.
この調子で油断せず行こう…
と言って終わりにしたいところだが
１つ提案がある
That's what I'd like to say,
but I do have one suggestion.
今このチームは強い
This team is strong.
Once our victory is certain,
we become unmotivated.
だからとも言えるが
勝ちが決まってからの—
モチベーションの低下が
しばしば目立つ
So I'm assigning a quota.
よって ノルマを課したい
Each man must score 20 points per game.
基本１試合１人 20点取ること
アハッ いーんじゃないっスか？
楽しそーだし！ ねー 青峰っち？
Why not? Sounds fun.
Right, Aominecchi?
あー… なんか めんどくせーな
Sounds like a pain in the ass.
Huh? You're not into the idea?
あれ？
なんかノリ悪くないっスか？
青峰っち むしろこういうの
いっつも燃えるじゃないっスか
Normally you're all over this kind of stuff.
Who cares, as long as we win?
だってよー
勝ってんならいーだろ 別に…
I don't like having to do this, either.
（赤司）オレも決して
好んで課すわけではない
But frankly, you seem especially unmotivated.
だが はっきり
言わせてもらえば—
モチベーションの低下が
特に目立つのは オマエだ
When scorers don't care about earning
points, it affects team morale.
スコアラーが得点に
執着しないようでは—
チームの士気にも
かかわる
ハアー… わーったよ
とにかく点取とりゃいいんだろ
Fine.
You want me to score, right?
（荻原(おぎわら)）
うーん… エースのサボリねえ
Your ace is skipping practice, huh?
（黒子）君は青峰君と
似ているので 何か分かるかと…
You're like Aomine-kun, so I
thought you might understand.
（荻原）
どんなムチャぶりだよ！
Are you out of your mind?
よく分かんねーけど—
I'm not sure, but he seems
different from Haizaki.
前聞いた灰崎ってヤツとは
違う気がすんなー
バスケを嫌いになった
わけじゃないんだろ？
He still likes basketball, right?
はい
Yes.
Maybe he stopped practicing
because he loves it so much.
（荻原）
むしろ誰よりも好きだから—
練習に出れなく
なったんじゃねーかなー？
All I can say is he's helped
you countless times before.
（荻原）
ただ まあはっきり言えるのは—
今まで彼には
何度も助けてもらったんだ
It's your turn to help him.
今度はオマエが助けてやれよ
それが仲間ってもんだろ
That's what friends do.
（黒子）はい…
Yes.
If we win two more games,
we're going to nationals.
（荻原）ウチも
あと２つ勝てば全中出場
あんときの約束
果たすまで負けんなよ！
You'd better not lose until
we fulfill our promise.
Of course.
（黒子）はい もちろんです
Later.
（荻原）じゃあな！
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
Ogiwara Shigehiro
Call Ended
Wow!
（観客１）すげえ！
（観客２）なんであれが入るんだ？
How did he make that?
The harder I try, the more
boring basketball becomes.
（青峰）頑張ったら頑張った分だけ
バスケがつまんなくなってくんだよ
Basketball's just a game, anyway.
バスケなんて
とどのつまりゲームだしな
We can throw the rest of the games...
これからは
試合もテキトーに流して…
（黒子）それはダメです
No, we can't.
What?!
んなぁ〜っ!? アイス？
Ice cream?
ボクは いつもみんなに
ついていくので精一杯です
I can barely keep up with
the rest of the team.
正直 青峰君の感覚は
分かりません
Honestly, I don't understand how you feel.
But no matter how much stronger you are,
けど どんなに力が離れてても
手加減されたり—
if I were your opponent, I would
never want you to hold back.
手を抜かれたりするのは—
ボクが相手だったら
絶対してほしくないです
それに 青峰君より
すごい人なんて すぐ現れますよ
Besides, you'll find someone
better than you soon enough.
（青峰）ははっ… そーだな
You're right.
The National Middle School Basketball
Tournament will now begin!
（会長）それではこれより—
全国中学校バスケットボール大会を
開催します！
（紫原）はー おなかへった…
早くおやつ食べたい…
I'm hungry.
I want my snack now.
（緑間）まだ開会式が
終わったばかりなのだよ
The opening ceremony just ended.
Can we get an interview?
（記者１）
インタビューよろしいですか？
（記者２）
今年のチームの仕上がりは？
How will your team finish this year?
Think you can win again?
（記者３）連覇に向けて
ひと言お願いします！
わわっ オレらもっスか!?
Us, too?
Akashi's amazing.
つか 赤司すげーなー
全部 模範解答で慣れたもんだ
He's used to giving model answers.
ハア…
Aomine!
（井上(いのうえ)）青峰ー
（青峰）あ？
Hey, it's been a while.
（青峰）おお 久しぶり！
元気してたかよ？
Who's that?
（黒子）あれは…
（さつき）ん…
How have you been?
（さつき）
あ あの人は上崎(かみざき)中の井上さん
That's Inoue-san from Kamizaki Middle School.
He's a power forward like Aomine-kun.
青峰君と同じ
パワーフォワードで—
去年やったときは
すごくいい勝負だったんだよ
When they played last
year, it was a great game.
（井上）今年こそ勝つからな！
（青峰）負けねーよ！
I'll beat you this year.
You can't beat me.
（荻原）
くーろこぉぉ〜！ ハハハッ
Kuroko!
Long time, no see!
（荻原）久しぶり！
（黒子）荻原君！
Ogiwara-kun!
It's been two years.
２年ぶりだな！
なんか雰囲気変わった？
You've changed.
荻原君も…
So have you.
Um...
あの… ご飯粒 ついてますよ
You've got rice on your face.
Huh?
（黒子）相変わらずですね
（荻原）まあ… その…
You haven't changed.
Yeah, well...
Now that we're here,
I don't know what to say.
いざ こうして会ってみると
何話していーか分かんねーな！
（黒子）そうですね
（荻原）けど まあ—
Yeah.
But I've really been looking forward to this.
楽しみには ずっとしてたんだ
ホントだぜ！
（荻原）絶対 勝ち上がるからな
（黒子）ボクもです
We'll definitely win.
So will we.
Let's do our best.
（黒子）頑張りましょう！
（荻原）うん！
Yeah.
The Teiko versus Kamizaki
game will now begin!
（審判）それではこれより—
帝光中 対 上崎中の試合を
始めます 礼！
Bow!
（選手一同）
よろしくお願いします！
Let's have a good game!
（青峰）なんだよ それ…
What is this?
Kamizaki
Teiko
もう戦うのも 諦めましたってか…
Have you given up already?
なんでだよ…
楽しみにしてたのに！
Why? I was looking forward to this.
オマエとなら
いい勝負ができるって…
I thought I'd at least have
a good game against you.
You don't get it.
分かってねーよ
オマエ…
自分がどんだけバケモンか
You're a monster.
No one can compete with you.
いるわけねえだろ
オマエとやれるヤツなんて…
Is that sarcasm?
嫌味かよ
Tetsu, it's no use.
（青峰）テツ… やっぱ ダメだわ
The only one who can beat me
オレに勝てるのは—
オレだけだ
is me.
（さつき）青峰君！
（青峰）うるせーよ
Aomine-kun!
Shut up. Leave me alone.
１人にしてくれ
（緑間）まさか 嫌な予感が
こんな形で当たるとはな…
I had a bad feeling,
but I wasn't expecting this.
Sorry, Kuroko. We lost.
（荻原）
ワリィ 黒子… 負けちまった
What?
（荻原）もうちょっと
だったん… だけどさっ…
We were so close, but...
あ〜… ダメだっ
悔しくてうまく話せねーわ
It's no use!
I'm so frustrated, I can't talk.
You guys won, right?
そっちは 勝ったんだろう？
はい
Yes.
（荻原）そっか… おめでとう
I see.
Congratulations.
I'd like to cheer you
on, but I have to leave.
応援行きてーけど—
このあとすぐ帰んなきゃ
なんねーんだ… ワリィ
Sorry.
（黒子）そんな…
何度も謝らないでください
You don't have to apologize so much.
そうだな…
Yeah, you're right.
うっ… ワリィ！
Sorry.
Preview
（黄瀬）
最近 絶好調っスね 紫原っち！
You've been on fire lately, Murasakibaracchi.
（紫原）うん 力がわいて
しょーがないんだよね〜
I just feel so powerful.
（黄瀬）ちょっと… だからって
お菓子食べ過ぎでしょー
Yeah, but you're still eating too much!
（紫原）食べなきゃ
やってらんないし…
I can't play if I don't eat.
We Are No Longer
なんかイライラする
I feel kind of irritated...